# Alaa Mohamed Khalil

Product Designer - UX / UI Designer - Graphic Designer

**SUMMARY** 

UI/UX Designer with Graphic design experience, I optimize business goals by solving human problems through user research and design. I believe a product is wholesome if different kinds of users feel seen during their interactions with the product. I do inclusive and accessible design, as well as cross-functional collaboration within teams. I Also experienced in Agile Methodology...

3rd Settlement Cairo, Egypt (+20) 1096 1844 67 alaamhmd2910@gmail.com LinkedIN - Behance

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# UI/UX Designer — The String

NOV 2022 - PRESENT

Developed and implemented a comprehensive tech-driven dashboard solution, integrating marketing strategies, to streamline workflow management for businesses.

# **UI/UX Designer** — Global Directions (PART TIME)

AUG 2022 - PRESENT

Design responsive websites (desktop, mobile), mobile applications, dashboards and digital interfaces.

# UI/UX Designer — Ayamedica

JUN 2022 - AUG 2022

Working on a medical mobile app and dashboard to help doctors, patients, and parents manage Their medical histories.

# UI/UX Designer — freelancer

SEP 2021 - PRESENT

Gather and evaluate user requirements in collaboration with Clients.

# **Graphic Designer** — freelancer

DEC 2018 - 2022

Designed visually captivating banners, posters, and website elements, I worked as a freelancer and I worked for companies also.

### **EDUCATION**

## **Minya University** — Bachelor

OCT 2014 - JUNE 2018

Bachelor's degree in Tourism and Hotels major in Tourism Guidance

# **Information Technology Institute (ITI)** — *Diploma*

DEC 2021 - MAR 2022

User research – User interface – User experience – Empathy mapping – Information Architecture – Usability Testing – Prototype, etc...

#### **TOOLS**

Figma

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe XD

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe Lightroom

Invision - Figjam - Miro

Coding: HTML - CSS

#### **SKILLS**

**UX** Research

**UX** Design

UI Design

Prototyping

**Usability Testing** 

Agile Methodology

Graphic Design

**Image Restoration** 

## **PERSONAL SKILLS**

Creativity

Communications

User empathy

Problem-solving

Detail-oriented

Multitasking

#### **LANGUAGES**

Arabic (mother Tongue) English (V.Good)

#### **PROJECTS**

# • The String

CRM, Leads Management tool Website

# Second Opinion

Medical website, mobile app and Dashboard

<u>Mobile App</u> - <u>Website</u>

# Al Hamriyah HCSC

Al Hamriyah Sports and Cultural Club mobile app  $\underline{\textbf{Mobile App}}$ 

## Arabella

Beauty Salon website, mobile app and Dashboard <u>Mobile App</u> – <u>Website</u>

#### • Nafeest Brands

ECommerce website

**Website** 

## • Student Center

Medical website, mobile app and Dashboard Website

#### Drs Space

Medical website, mobile app and Dashboard Mobile App - Website.

#### Taktib

Scenario evaluation website

**Website** 

## Orange, Spotify Advertising

Graphic work collaborating with Al
First Ad Link - Sec Ad Link

## GeoSports

Sports tracking, shop Mobile app

## Promoterss

Digital Marketing website

**Website** 

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Introduction to Agile
 Development and Scrum

Coursera/IBM - 2024

• UX Design Fundamental

MaharaTech - 2021

• Design In Figma App

Barmej - 2022

• Foundation Of UX Design

Coursera - 2022

 Build Wireframes and Low-Fidelity Prototypes

Coursera - 2023

Start the UX Design
 Process: Empathize,
 Define, and Ideate

Coursera - 2023